Guide to the Ephim Fogel papers,1940-1989.
Fogel, Ephim papers,1940-1989
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ephim Fogel papers, 1940-1989.
14-12-2711
Ephim Fogel, 1920-1992.
1.9 cubic feet.
Correspondence, subject files, a volume, and a photographic negative.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and subject files pertaining chiefly to Fogel's career as Professor of English at Cornell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of English, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence and subject files pertaining chiefly to Fogel's career at Cornell. Letters and documents touch on departmental policies and procedures; promotion and tenure discussions; recommendations for students and colleagues; lecture notes, reading lists, syllabi. Special files concern Fogel's work in creating the Paul Gottschalk Memoral Lecture series honoring his deceased colleague. Materials relating to Fogel's own scholarly projects include substantial files on his collaboration with David V. Erdman in editing Evidence for Authorship for the Cornell University Press. Also, a volume of the complete works of Edmund Spenser owned and annotated by both Fogel and William Strunk; a photographic negative of a bookplate honoring John Alban Finch, and letter from Fogel to Elizabeth Murphy concerning the Finch Fund and bookplate.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fogel, Ephim.; Erdman, David V.; Finch, John Alban, 1929-1967.; Gottschalk, Paul, 1939-1977.; Murphy, Elizabeth.; Strunk, William, 1869-1946.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University Press.; Cornell University. English Dept.; Paul Gottschalk Memorial Lectures.
Subjects:
English literature--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- C Correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- D Correspondence, 1962-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- E Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Endel, Peggy Goodman (2), 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Endel (4), original draft with Mr. Fogel's comments; appendix to chapter on anality (III) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- F Correspondence, 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Gottschalk, Paul, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- H Correspondence, 1961-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- K Correspondence, 1945-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- M Correspondence, 1963-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mc Correspondence, 1964-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Merod, J., 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Morgan, Robert, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- N Correspondence, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Nathan, George Jean - Award, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Pelli, Moshe, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- R Correspondence, 1963-1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- S Correspondence, 1961-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20-23)
- Schwartz, S, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Stallworthy, Jan, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
- Stretkowicz, Victor, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- T Correspondence, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Thiesmeyer, Elaine (Box 1, Folder 29)
- U Correspondence, 1961, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- V Correspondence, 1967-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
- W Correspondence, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Waller, Martha, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Y, Z Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Admissions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Adrian Tinsley, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Afro-American Studies and Center, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Attribution Volume, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Bibliographies and Syllabi (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Evidence for Authorship Correspondence - Erdman-Fogel, Cornell Press, etc., 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 41-46)
- English Department - not current, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- English Department notices, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Faculty Collegium on Literature, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Graduate - Procedural Guide - courses, notices, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Literature 101-102: meetings, notices (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Malory Eng. 111, Sec. 15, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- "The Mythical Sorrows of Astrophil" - notes on offprints, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- "The Mythical Sorrows of Astrophil", 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Nominating Committee, 1961-1973 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Othello offprints - notes, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Paper at NCTE (National Council of Teachers of English), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- President, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Professors-at-Large - A.D. White (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Procedural Guide for Graduate Study in English at Cornell, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Reserve List, English 309 - syllabi, exams, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Grant - Society for Humanities, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Society for Humanities - Professors-at-Large (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Volume: The Globe Edition - Complete Works of Edmund Spenser, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Correspondence: A-Ad, 1946-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Al-Av, 1944-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: A. R. Ammons, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: A. R. Ammons, 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Ba-Bicknell, 1946-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Biedzrycka-Br, 1956-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: Bu, 1959-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: C, 1946-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: D, 1961-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: E, 1959-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: English Department [Cornell University], 1965-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: F, 1949-1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: John Finch, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence: Ga-Goodhart, 1967-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence: Paul Gottschalk, 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence: Gr-Gu, 1959-1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence: H, 1959-1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence: J, 1959-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence: K-Kas, 1963-1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence: Kat-Ku, 1945-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence: L, 1945-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence: Ma-Mc, 1957-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Correspondence: Me-Mu, 1962-1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Correspondence: N, 1964-1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Correspondence: Nabokov, 1977-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Correspondence: David Novarr, 1962-1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Correspondence: O, 1944-1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Correspondence: P, 1945-1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Correspondence: Phi Beta Kappa, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Correspondence: R, 1946-1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Correspondence: Sa-She, 1959-1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Correspondence: Shr, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Correspondence: Si-Su, 1944-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Correspondence: T, 1953-1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Correspondence: U, 1946-1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Correspondence: V, 1961-1981 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Correspondence: W, 1940-1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Correspondence: Z, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Correspondence: No Surname, 1959-1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Correspondence: E. F. Academic Career, 1941-1986 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Correspondence: E. F. Poetry and Writings, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Correspondence: E. F. Poetry and Writings, 1946-1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Correspondence: E. F. Poetry and Writings, 1970-1992 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Journal, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Subject Files: John Finch essay correspondence, 1963-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Subject Files: John Finch essay, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Subject Files: Mandelshtam, 1972-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Subject Files: Nabokov, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Subject Files: Pushkin, 1945-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Subject Files: Shakespeare: Table of Green Fields, 1956-1959; 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Subject Files: Shakespeare: Conferences, 1963-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Subject Files: Yeats, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Cornell University English Department: Publications lists, 1957-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Cornell University English Department: Broadsides, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Cornell University: Academic Freedom and Responsibility, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
- Cornell Univerisity: Concordances, 1966-1980 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
- Cornell University: Tenure Procedures, 1970-1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Cornell University: Faculty Miscellany, 1957-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Cornell University: Miscellany, 1961-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- English Department: Faculty Miscellany, 1966-1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- English Department: English Course Requirements, 1964-1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- English Department: Course Lists, Course Correspondence, 1964-1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- English Department: Course Outlines: English 101-102, 127, 227, 241, 1961-1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- English Department: Course Outlines: English 251, 270, 271, 272, 290, 303, 309, 319, 1958-1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- English Department: Course Outlines: English 327, 368, 427, 428, 491, 500, 594, 627, Seminar, 1968-1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- English Department: Student Papers, 1978; 19-- (Box 3, Folder 24)
- English Course Exams, 1954-1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- English Course: Student Comments, Course Evaluation Forms, 1953; 1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- RESTRICTED: Personnel Files (Box 4)